Mss.Ms.Coll.151
American Philosophical Society
Jasper Yeates Papers
Bulk, 1760-1816
1738-1910
Mss.Ms.Coll.151
American Philosophical Society
3.0 Linear feet
Jasper Yeates (1745-1817) was a lawyer and Pennsylvania Supreme Court justice, one of the state's most successful colonial-era legal practitioners. After moving to Lancaster County in 1765, he became active in colonial and early federal affairs, first by supporting the Revolutionary struggle and later by serving as one of Lancaster's delegates to the State Convention of 1787, which ratified the U.S. Constitution. The Jasper Yeates Papers (1728-1910, bulk 1760-1816) consist mainly of correspondence and business and court/legal records related to the Yeates family. The bulk of this three linear foot collection reflect Yeates’ personal life as husband, father, son, and friend, as well as his professional life as lawyer and judge in Pennsylvania; much of the material dated after Yeates’ death was created by children and/or grandchildren.
Yeates, Jasper
Biographical/Historical note
Jasper Yeates (1745-1817) was a lawyer and Pennsylvania Supreme Court justice, one of the state's most successful colonial-era legal practitioners. After moving to Lancaster County in 1765, he became active in colonial and early federal affairs, first by supporting the Revolutionary struggle and later by serving as one of Lancaster's delegates to the State Convention of 1787, which ratified the U.S. Constitution.
Yeates was born in Philadephia on April 9, 1745, to John and Elizabeth (Sidbotham) Yeates. He studied at the College of Philadelphia (now the University of Pennsylvania), where he received a Bachelor of Arts degree in 1761. Upon graduation he continued his studies at the college, earning a Master of Arts two years later (1763). He was admitted to the bar in 1765 and subsequently moved to the city of Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Yeates went on to become one of the most successful legal practitioners in the state. His notoriety earned him the commission of Judge of the Supreme Court of Pennsylvania on March 21, 1791. He served in that position until his death in 1817. Judge Yeates prepared notes of judicial proceedings in which he took part, with the intent to publish. They were printed after he died.
From 1802 to 1805, Yeates was involved in an impeachment trial along PA Supreme Court Chief Justice Edward Shippen and Judge Thomas Smith. The three men were charged with illegally sentencing Thomas Passmore to thirty days in jail and for imposing a $50 fine for a “supposed contempt.” All three men were acquitted.
Yeates was one of the foremost patriots from the inception of the Revolutionary struggle. He served as chairman of the Committee of Correspondence of Lancaster in 1776. He was also one of Lancaster County's delegates to the State Convention of 1787, which ratified the U.S. Constitution.
Jasper married Sarah Burd in Lancaster on December 30, 1767. Sarah was the eldest daughter of Colonel James Burd and his wife, Sarah Shippen, who was daughter to Edward Shippen of Lancaster and sister to Chief Justice Edward Shippen. They moved to 24 South Queen Street in 1775 and raised 10 children over a period of 37-plus years.
Many of their children grew up to marry and have families of their own. Their firstborn, Mary Yeates, arrived in in 1770. In 1791, she married Charles Smith, son of Rev. William Smith, the provost of the College of Philadelphia. Charles became judge for the Ninth Judicial District of Pennsylvania and in 1820 was commissioned judge of the city of Lancaster. Together he and Mary had eight children.
Son John Yeates was born in 1772, and followed in his father’s footsteps by graduating with a Bachelor of Arts degree from the College of Pennsylvania in 1792. He became a lawyer and married Eliza Buckley, daughter of Daniel Buckley. They had no children.
Daughter Elizabeth Yeates was born in 1778. In 1808 she married Redmond Conyngham, a prominent literary figure and the son of David Hayfield Conyngham and grandson of Redmond Conyngham, Esq., of Ireland. Together Elizabeth and Redmond had six children.
Jasper and Sarah also had two daughters who never married: Margaret (born 1780) and Catherine (born 1782). Five of the Yeates' 10 children died in infancy.
As a result of Jasper’s political and judicial duties and travels, he and Sarah—whom he called “Dear Sally”—exchanged many letters throughout their marriage. In these letters, the couple expressed their love, shared news, and made family decisions. Yeates also exchanged many letters with his children and grandchildren.
Jasper became involved with St. James Episcopal Church in Lancaster, serving the congregation as warden and vestryman. He died on March 14, 1817, and was buried at the churchyard of St. James. Sarah died in 1829 and is buried near him in the same graveyard.
Bibliography Jordon, John W. Colonial and Revolutionary Families of Pennsylvania (Philadelphia: Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1911), p. 663-668.
Lancaster Historical Society. “Sarah and Jasper Yeates: A Lifetime of Romance.” Accessed March 15, 2011. http://www.lancasterhistory.org/index.php?option=com_content&view=article&id=368&Itemid=172.
RootsWeb’s World Connect Project.
Warren, Charles. History of the Harvard Law School and of Early Legal Conditions in America (New York: Lewis Publishing Company, 1908), p. 199-200.
Scope and Contents note
The Jasper Yeates Papers (1738-1910, bulk 1760-1816) consist mainly of correspondence and business and court/legal records related to the Yeates family. The bulk of this three linear foot collection reflect Yeates’ personal life as husband, father, son, and friend, as well as his professional life as lawyer and judge in Pennsylvania; much of the material dated after Yeates’ death was created by children and/or grandchildren.
This collection is rich in materials related to colonial-era and early-federal-era Pennsylvania history. Those studying the Pennsylvania judiciary and colonial-era slavery in south-central Pennsylvania will find this collection particularly valuable.
Materials of particular interest include decades-long correspondence between Yeates and his wife, Sarah; orders to testify at Yeates’ impeachement trial; correspondence with Pennsylvania Supreme Court Chief Justice Edward Shippen; a description of the Native American attack on Fort Granville during the French and Indian War; and legal documents related to slavery in Lancaster County and Philadelphia.
The material is organized into six series (Correspondence, Jasper and Sarah Yeates; Correspondence, general; Business records; Court and legal records; “Slavery material”; and Miscellaneous records), with each series arranged chronologically.
Early American History Note
The Jasper Yeates Collection contains a range of documents from this prominent Pennsylvania lawyer and judge, most of which are from the early republic. Because the collection is new to the APS, the MOLE entry contains an item level catalogue of the collection's content. Yeates was active during the American Revolution as a leader of opposition to Great Britain in Lancaster, Pennsylvania. After the Revolution, he became an Associate Justice on the State Supreme Court. He was also related through marriage to the Shippen and Burd families. This collection contains personal letters written between Jasper and his wife Sally. There are also legal records and court proceedings. Within these documents, there is an account of a slave insurrection in Lancaster County during the American Revoltuion.
Related Archival Materials note
The Lancaster County Historical Society (Lancaster, Pennsylvania) houses the Jasper Yeates Colonial Law Library and has additional manuscript materials relating to Jasper Yeates and the Yeates Family.
Burd, Edward Shippen, 1779-1848; Burd, Elizabeth; Burd, Joseph; Cox, Tench; Shippen, Edward Jr.; Shippen, Joseph Jr.; Tilghman, Edward, 1750-1815; Whelan, William; Yeates, Elizabeth; Yeates, John; Yeates, Margaret; Yeates, Sarah Burd; African American; Business Records and Accounts; Family Correspondence; General Correspondence; Lancaster County (Pa.)--History; Law; Legal Records; Marriage and Family Life; Pennsylvania --History --French and Indian War, 1755-1763; Pennsylvania History; Pennsylvania Supreme Court; Political Correspondence; Seven Years' War; Slavery -- Pennsylvania.; Social Life and Custom; United States--History--French and Indian War, 1755-1763
- Series I. Correspondence, Jasper and Sarah Yeates, 1768-1816
  Scope and Contents note
  Letters to and from Jasper and Sarah Yeates over a period of almost fifty years. Letters describe family life, Jasper’s travels, and other matters.
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1767 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1768 January (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1768 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1768 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1768 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1768 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1768 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 October 28 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1769 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1770 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1771 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1772 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1773 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1774 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1775 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1777 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1779 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1780 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1781 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1782 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1783 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1784 May - 1784 July (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1785 January - 1785 September (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1785 September - 1785 October (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1786 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1787 January - 1787 April (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1787 May - 1787 December (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1788 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1789 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1790 September - 1790 October (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1790 November (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1790 January - 1790 July (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1790 January - 1790 July (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1791 January - 1791 July (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1791 July - 1791 September (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1791 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1791 January - 1791 December (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1792 January (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1792 April - 1792 May (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1792 September (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1793 January - 1793 April (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1793 April - 1793 October (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1793 October (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1794 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1795 January (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1795 April - 1795 December (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1796 September - 1796 October (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1797 March - 1797 May (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1797 October - 1797 December (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1797 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1798 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1799 March - 1799 May (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1799 October - 1799 December (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1800 March - 1800 September (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1800 October (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1800 December (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1800 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1802 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1803 March 6 - 1803 April 25 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1803 April 29 - 1803 December 21 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1804 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1805 March - 1805 August (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1805 September - 1805 October (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1806 March - 1806 October (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1806 December (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1807 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1808 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1809 March - 1809 July (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1809 August - 1809 September (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1809 October - 1809 December (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1810 January - 1810 September (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1810 December (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1811 February - 1811 September (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1811 November - 1811 December (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1812 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1812 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1813 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1813 January - 1813 July (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1813 October - 1813 December (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1814 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Yeates, Sarah to Jasper Yeates, 1814 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1815 January - 1815 November (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1815 December (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, 1816 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Sarah Yeates, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Series II. Correspondence, general, 1728-1902
  Letters to and from members of the Yeates family (including descendants) and friends. Major correspondents include Edward Shippen, John Yeates, Edward Burd, Joseph Shippen, Charles Smith, Margaret Yeates, J.D. Britton, Charles Biddle, Tench Cox, and others. Of note are letters related to Jasper Yeates’ impeachment trial.
  - Yeates, George to _______, 1738 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Yeates, John to Jasper Yeates, 1759 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Yeates, Betsy to Jasper Yeates, 1759-1761 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Yeates, John to Jasper Yeates, 1759-1765 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Yeates, Donaldson to Jasper Yeates, 1759-1783 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Yeates, John to Jasper Yeates, 1765 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Yeates, John to _______, 1765 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Snead, Edward to John Yeates, 1765 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Yeates, Sarah to "Dear Brother" [John Burd ?], 1766 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Anderson, E. to Sarah Yeates, 1766 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Grime, Mark to Jasper Yeates, 1766 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Snead, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1766 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - General business correspondence, 1768 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Shippen, Joseph to Jasper Yeates, 1769 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - West, William to Jasper Yeates, 1769 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - General business correspondence, 1769 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - General business correspondence, 1770 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Shippen, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1770-1804 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - General business correspondence, 1771 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - General business correspondence, 1772 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Shippen, Joseph to Jasper Yeates, 1772 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - General business correspondence, 1773 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - General business correspondence, 1773 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Shippen, Joseph to Jasper Yeates, 1773 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - General business correspondence, 1774 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Gibbon, John to Jasper Yeates, 1775 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - General business correspondence, 1775 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - West, William to Jasper Yeates, 1775 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Norton, William to Jasper Yeates, 1776 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - General business correspondence, 1776 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Coleman, Robert to Jasper Yeates, 1778 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Shippen, Joseph to Jasper Yeates, 1778 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - General business correspondence, 1779 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Shippen, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1780-1806 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - General business correpsondence, 1780 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General business correspondence, 1781 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Price, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1782 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General business correspondence, 1783 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Shippen, Footman to Jasper Yeates, 1784 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Biddle, Charles to Jasper Yeates, 1785 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Coleman, Robert to Jasper Yeates, 1786 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Tilghman, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1786 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Shippen, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1786 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - General business correspondence, 1787 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Coxe, Tench to Edward Shippen, 1787 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Jones, Owen to Jasper Yeates, 1787 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Yeates, Jasper to Edward Shippen, 1787 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sheldon, Richard to Jasper Yeates, 1788 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Shippen, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1788 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Shippen, Joseph to Jasper Yeates, 1789 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Coleman, Robert to Jasper Yeates, 1789 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Yeates, Jasper to John Shippen, Jr., 1789 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Coleman, Robert to Jasper Yeates, 1790 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Shippen, John to Jasper Yeates, 1790 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Smith, Charles to Jasper Yeates, 1790 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Shippen, Joseph to Jasper Yeates, 1791 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - General correspondence, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Lankzinger, Paul to Charles Smith, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Coleman, Robert to Jasper Yeates, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Miller, Whalen to Jasper Yeates, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Shippen,, Joseph to Jasper Yeates, 1793 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Smith, Mary to Jasper Yeates, 1794 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - General business correspondence, 1794 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Shippen, John to Jasper Yeates, 1794 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Shippen, John to Jasper and Sarah Yeates, 1795 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - General business correspondence, 1795 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Shippen, John to Jasper Yeates, 1795 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - General correspondence, 1796 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Shippen, John to Jasper Yeates, 1795 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Smith, Charles to _______, 1797 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - General correspondence, 1798 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Shippen, John to Sarah Yeates, 1799 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - General correspondence, 1799 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - General correspondence, 1800 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - General correspondence, 1801 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Burd, Edward Shippen to Jasper Yeates, 1801 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - General business corrspondence, 1801 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - General correspondence, 1802 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - General business correspondence, 1802 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - General business correspondence, 1803 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - General correspondence, 1803 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - General correspondence, 1804 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - General business correspondence, 1804 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Smith, Jasper Yeates to Jasper Yeates, 1804 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Tilghman, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1804 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - General business correspondence, 1805 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Smith, Charles to Jasper Yeates, 1805 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Cox, Daniel W. to Jasper Yeates, 1806 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - General business correspondence, 1806 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - General correspondence, 1806 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General business correspondence, 1807 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence, 1807 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - General business correspondence, 1808 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - General correspondence, 1808 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Smith, William W. to Jasper Yeates, 1809 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Yeates, Sarah to John Yeates, 1809 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - General business correspondence, 1810 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - General correspondence, 1810 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Burd, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1811 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - General business correspondence, 1811 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - General correspondence, 1811 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Tilghman, W. to Jasper Yeates, 1812 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - General correspondence, 1812 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Smith, Charles to Jasper Yeates, 1813 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - General correspondence, 1814 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - General business correspondence, 1814 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - McElwee, J. to James McElwee, 1815 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - General business correspondence, 1815 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, 1815 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - General business correspondence, 1816 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tilghman, Edward to Jasper Yeates, 1816 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - General business correspondence, 1817 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - General correspondence, 1817 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Burd, Edward Shippen to Sarah Yeates, 1818-1840 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - General correspondence, 1819 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Yeates, Sarah to John Yeates, 1821 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Burd, Edward Shippen to Sarah Yeates, 1822 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - General correspondence, 1822 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - General correspondence, 1823 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Cadwallader, Thomas to Thomas B. McElwee, 1824 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Smith, Mary to Sarah Yeates, 1825 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Smith, Mary to Sarah Yeates, 1826 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Burd, Edward to John Yeates, 1826 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Smith,Mary to Sarah Yeates, 1827 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - General correspondence, 1829 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - General correspondence, 1830 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Britton, J. B. to John Yeates, 1826, 1837-1840, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Shippen, Henry to Catherine Yeates, 1831 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - General business correspondence, 1831 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - General correspondence, 1833 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Whelan, Maria to Townsend Whelan, 1834 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Cox, Daniel W. to Catheine Yeates, 1835 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - General correspondence, 1836 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - White, William to Margaret Yeates, 1836 (Box 7, Folder 2)